## **David Robles**

Contact

INFORMATION Phone: (415) 515-4764 Email: drobles@gmail.com

Twitter: @davidrobles

Linkedin: http://www.linkedin.com/in/drobles

Summary

Software Engineer with strong focus on tackling engineering challenges, writing quality software and with strong grasp of software architecture, advanced software engineering principles and design patterns.

I recently completed an MSc and PhD in Computer Science from the University of Essex, where I conducted research focused on Reinforcement Learning, Simulation-Based Search, Evolutionary Algorithms and Games. During this time I was also a Teaching Assistant in several courses in programming and web application development.

I'm currently a Software Engineer at dotloop, where I work primarily as a Java backend developer responsible for designing and implementing new features and RESTful APIs. In my free time, I love programming in Ruby, Rails, Python, and more recently I've been diving into functional programming.

### EDUCATION

# PhD Computer Science

University of Essex Colchester, United Kingdom

2009 - 2013

Thesis: "Simulation-Based Search and Learning in Games"

### **MSc Computer Science**

University of Essex Colchester, United Kingdom 2007 - 2008

Software engineering theme, passed with distinction.

## **BSc Information Systems Engineering**

Institute of Technology and Higher Education of Monterrey Hermosillo, Mexico 2001 -  $2006\,$ 

### EXPERIENCE

## Software Engineer

DotLoop

San Francisco, CA January 2013 - Present

- Java backend developer.
- Design and implementation of new features and RESTful APIs in Spring MVC.

## Teaching Assistant

University of Essex Colchester, United Kingdom October 2009 - March 2012 Preparation, marking and teaching of classes and laboratories for the following undergraduate and postgraduate courses:

CE705 - Programming in Java, Autumn 2011.

CE320 - Large Scale Software Scale Systems and Extreme Programming, Autumn 2011.

CE218 - Computer Game Programming, Spring 2011.

CE152 - Object-Oriented Programming, Spring 2011.

CE705 - Programming in Java, Autumn 2010.

CE212 - Web Application Programming, Spring 2010.

CE112 - Procedural and Object-Oriented Programming, Spring 2010.

CE705 - Programming in Java, Autumn 2009.

## Systems Administrator

Camisa Development Group Hermosillo, Mexico March 2006 - May 2007

Network Administrator, Windows Server 2003, Active Directory, VPN, CRM Software, Sage SalesLogix.

#### SKILLS

Programming languages: Java, Ruby, Python, PHP, C.

Web Development: Ruby on Rails, Spring MVC, JSP/Servlets, JavaScript, CSS.

Testing: JUnit, RSpec, Mockito. Databases: MySQL, PostgreSQL. Cloud: Amazon EC2/S3, Heroku. Version Control: Git, SVN. OS: Unix/Linux, Mac OS X.

## AWARDS

Scholarship for MSc and PhD Computer Science degrees from the National Council of Science and Technology of Mexico.

### CERTIFICATIONS

Cisco Certified Network Associate (CCNA), February 2006. Microsoft Certified Systems Administrator (MCSA), May 2007.